<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Lovelace Gosling</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="first_name">Ada Lovelace</string>
    <string name="second_name">James Gosling</string>
    <string name="description_img_ada_lovelace">Picture of Ada Lovelace</string>
    <string name="description_img_james_gosling">Picture of James Gosling</string>
    <string name="description_ada_lovelace">
        Augusta Ada King, Countess of Lovelace (10 December 1815 – 27 November 1852), 
        born Augusta Ada Byron and now commonly known as Ada Lovelace, was an English 
        mathematician and writer chiefly known for her work on Charles Babbage\'s early 
        mechanical general-purpose computer, the Analytical Engine Her notes on the engine 
        include what is recognised as the first algorithm intended to be carried out by a 
        machine. Because of this, she is often described as the world\'s first computer 
        programmer. Lovelace was born 10 December 1815 as the only legitimate child of 
        the poet Lord Byron and his wife Anne Isabella Byron. All Byron\'s other children 
        were born out of wedlock. Byron separated from his wife a month after Ada was 
        born and left England forever four months later, eventually dying of disease in 
        theGreek War of Independence when Ada was eight years old. Ada\'s mother remained 
        bitter at Lord Byron and promoted Ada\'s interest in mathematics and logic in an 
        effort to prevent her from developing what she saw as the insanity seen in her 
        father, but Ada remained interested in him despite this (and was, upon her 
        eventual death, buried next to him at her request).
        
        \n\nAda described her approach as \"poetical science\" and herself as an \"Analyst 
        (&amp; Metaphysician)\". As a young adult, her mathematical talents led her to an 
        ongoing working relationship and friendship with fellow British mathematician 
        Charles Babbage, and in particular Babbage\'s work on the Analytical Engine. 
        Between 1842 and 1843, she translated an article by Italian military engineer 
        Luigi Menabrea on the engine, which she supplemented with an elaborate set of 
        notes of her own, simply called Notes. These notes contain what many consider 
        to be the first computer program—that is, an algorithm designed to be carried 
        out by a machine. Lovelace\'s notes are important in the early history of computers. 
        She also developed a vision on the capability of computers to go beyond mere 
        calculating or number-crunching while others, including Babbage himself, focused 
        only on those capabilities. Ada\'s mind-set of \"poetical science\" led her to ask 
        basic questions about the Analytical Engine (as shown in her notes) examining 
        how individuals and society relate to technology as a collaborative tool.
        
        \n\n*From http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace
        
    </string>
     <string name="description_james_gosling">
       James Arthur Gosling, OC (born May 19, 1955) is a Canadian computer scientist, 
       best known as the father of the Java programming language.
       
       \n\nIn 1977, Gosling received a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science from the 
       University of Calgary. In 1983, he earned a Ph.D in Computer Science fromCarnegie 
       Mellon University, supervised by Bob Sproull. While working towards his doctorate, 
       he wrote a version of Emacs called Gosling Emacs(Gosmacs), and before joining Sun 
       Microsystems he built a multi-processor version of Unix[7] while at Carnegie Mellon University, 
       as well as several compilersand mail systems.
       
       \n\nBetween 1984 and 2010, Gosling was with Sun Microsystems. He is known as the father of the Java 
       programming language.
       
       \n\nOn April 2, 2010, Gosling left Sun Microsystems which had recently been acquired by the Oracle 
       Corporation. Regarding why he left, Gosling cited reductions in pay, status, and decision-making 
       ability, change of role, and ethical challenges. He has since taken a very critical stance towards 
       Oracle in interviews, noting that "During the integration meetings between Sun and Oracle, where 
       we were being grilled about the patent situation between Sun and Google, we could see the Oracle 
       lawyer's eyes sparkle." Later, during the Oracle vs. Google trial over Android, he clarified his 
       position saying "Just because Sun didn't have patent suits in our genetic code doesn't mean we 
       didn't feel wronged. While I have differences with Oracle, in this case they are in the right. 
       Google totally slimed Sun. We were all really disturbed, even Jonathan [Schwarz]: he just decided 
       to put on a happy face and tried to turn lemons into lemonade, which annoyed a lot of folks at Sun."
       
       \n\nOn March 28, 2011, James Gosling announced on his blog that he had been hired by Google. Five 
       months later, he announced that he joined a startup called Liquid Robotics.
       
       \n\nGosling is listed as an advisor at the Scala company Typesafe Inc. and Strategic Advisor for Eucalyptus.
       
       \n\n*From http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Gosling
       
       
    </string>

</resources>